[Music]
[Música]
Yeah, okay, Jesus Manuel, how about you
Sí vale Jesús Manuel pues te parece que
tell me a little bit about that
me cuentes un poquito sobre esa
exclusive you recently published in the
exclusiva que diste hace poco en el
newspaper? I don't miss a single article of
diario que no me pierdo ni un artículo
yours, and I don't want you to know about my people either. We'll
tuyo y mi gente tampoco quiero que lo
comment. If not, I'll comment on it. Javi from
comentamos si no la comento yo Javi de
Hablando Claro. I don't know if you know him, but he
Hablando claro No sé si lo conoce pero
also comments, but I also have to
también Comenta pero también le tengo
thank him from here because the
que dar las gracias desde aquí porque la
truth is that he comments a lot and always has
verdad que Comenta mucho y siempre tiene
a favorable opinion. We don't always have to
una opinión favorable que no siempre se
agree. Let's say that in the
tiene que estar de acuerdo decir que al
end, with all due respect, you don't
final con respeto decir no se tiene
always have to agree, but I
porque estar siempre de acuerdo pero
have to thank him. But I can't
tengo que dar las gracias pero yo no
reach him because I didn't have contact. It
localizado porque no tenía contacto
would be very, it would be very boring. If we all
sería muy sería muy aburrido Si todos
thought the same, if not, we wouldn't have
pensáramos igual si no No tendríamos
anything to discuss. No, not even to talk about. Let's
nada que discutir No ni que hablar
see about the issue of
a ver sobre el tema de la situación
Ortega Cano's civil status. Now we're going to be
civil de Ortega Cano que ahora vamos a
talking about this supposed
estar hablando sobre esta supuesta
lawsuit that's going to be filed or not. What would
demanda que se va a interponer o no cuál
be, Jesus Manuel, the real civil status
sería Jesús Manuel la situación civil
of Ortega Cano and
real en estos momentos de Ortega Cano y
Ana María Aldón at the moment? Look at this. This is an
Ana María aldón Mira este Este es un
article that we published last week in the
artículo que sacamos la semana pasada en
newspaper and what is already being reported as
es diario y lo que se cuenta ya como
information is that José Ortega Cano and Ana
información es que José ortelano y Ana
María the  Don are already divorced and
María el don están ya divorciados y se
have divorced when one wants to get
han divorciado cuando uno se quiere
divorced it can be a process of mutual
divorciar puede ser un proceso de mutuo
agreement meaning that both parties
acuerdo es decir que las dos partes
agree to bring the same
están de acuerdo en llevar al mismo
lawyer and they will not get to the litigation
abogado y no van a llegar al contencioso
or if they do not agree then it has to
o si no están de acuerdo pues se tiene
go to litigation and in that case
que pasar al contencioso y en ese caso
one party has to bring a
una parte tiene que llevar a un director
technical director or lawyer and the other party has to
técnico o abogado y la otra parte tiene
bring another in this case both
que llevar a otro en este caso las dos
parties agreed that it should be
partes estaban de acuerdo en que fuera
amicable or by mutual agreement it was the same
amistoso o mutuo acuerdo era el mismo
lawyer for both parties among other
abogado para las dos partes entre otras
things because Jesus from here has told us and it
cosas porque Jesús de acá nos ha dicho y
is what is said in the article that he
es lo que se cuenta en el artículo que
is a stingy guy who never Well it
es un tío roñoso que nunca Bueno se
can be assured that he never dreamed that he was going
puede asegurar que nunca soñó que se iba
to stay in the situation in which he was
a quedar en la situación en la que se
going to stay among other things because
iba a quedar entre otras cosas porque se
José Ortega Cano stays he is going to pay him he
queda José Ortega Cano le va a pagar se
keeps custody the child he keeps
queda con una custodia el niño se queda
shared custody I do
compartida
not know if it is 10 days with the mother and days
no sé si son 10 días con la madre y días
with the father but apart from the fact that in that
con el padre pero aparte de que en ese
case to be shared José Ortega Cano would
caso a ser compartida José Ortega Canon
not have to contribute anything to the other
no tendría que aportar nada a la otra
party in terms of maintenance or
parte en cuanto ni a manutención ni a ni
any tension Well  hopefully here No,
ninguna tensión Pues con suerte acá No
apart from that,
aparte le va a pagar todos los gastos
Ana María Aldo will pay for all of her
extraescolares Ana María Aldo para su
son's extracurricular school expenses and apart from that, she will give him a pension, I
hijo y aparte le va a pasar una pensión
think it is, I think I published 1200
creo que son yo creo que publiqué 1200
euros or 1000 euros, I don't remember
euros o mil euros no me acuerdo muy bien
the amount very well because it was like 10 days ago
la cantidad porque hace ya como 10 días
1200 euros apart from paying her everything that has to do
1200 euros aparte de pagarle todo lo que
with her son and with the
tenga que ver con su hijo y con el
time that he is with her, she will pay him that, she
tiempo que esté con ella le va a pagar
will give him that pension So
esa esa le va a dar esa pensión Entonces
what happens when one reaches an agreement,
qué pasa con cuando uno llega un acuerdo
all sentences in
todas las sentencias en el derecho
Spanish law have to be executed, you
español se tienen que ejecutar Usted
have to ratify, that is to say, you receive
tienen que ratificar es decir Tú recibes
the divorce and you have to go to court to
el divorcio y se tiene que a juzgados a
ratify that sentence, but that is a
ratificar esa sentencia pero eso es un
procedure, that is to say, simply saying, you
trámite es decir simplemente decir no
cannot say, well, I attest to the
puede decir pues sí doy fe notaría el
total, a notary or a notary, in this case it cannot
total o notario en este caso no puede
be a notary because there is a minor. So
ser notario porque hay un menor Entonces
when it is a minor, divorces
cuando es un menos los divorcios no se
cannot be done in a notary's office, it has to be
pueden hacer en la notaría tiene que ser
in court because the
en lo juzgados porque se vela por el
interest of the minor is looked after, then the
interés del menor entonces interviene el
prosecutor intervenes, but ratification is a process, the
fiscal pero ratificar es un proceso el
last process to be divorced, that
último proceso para estar divorciado eso
is an issue that I believe is more  or less than I have been
es un tema que yo creo que más o menos a
able to make clear
que he podido quedar claro
There is an amicable agreement and
Hay una un acuerdo amistoso y
basically it is very good no Or do you
básicamente está muy bien no O sea tú
understand more beneficial for her
que entiendes más beneficioso para ella
because of course in a in a
porque desde luego en una en una un
divorce where there is
divorcio donde hay una custodia
shared custody of the minor Well, I have him 10
compartida del menor Pues yo lo tengo 10
days, these 10 days everything is for me and
días yo estos 10 días todo es para mí y
the 10 days that the mother is
los 10 días que está la madre todas para
there, apart from that she pays for everything
allá pues aparte de eso le paga todo lo
extraordinary that the minor has, the
extraordinario que tenga el menor el
school logically because these people
colegio lógicamente porque esta gente
are private and everything that has to do
son de privado y todo lo que tenga que
with the extraordinary for the minor and
ver con lo extraordinario del menor y
apart from all that
aparte de todo eso
1200 euros for Ana María, the gift super
1200 euros para Ana María el don súper
good Until the child is not 18 years old but
bien Hasta que el niño tenga no 18 años
is in his
sino que sea
twenties that they already work, that they
veintitantos años que ya trabajen que
are independent, it is clear that when we
sea independiente es que claro cuando se
talk about 18 years, the thing about 18
habla de los 18 años se lo de los 18
years no longer makes much sense, the issue
años ya no tiene mucho sentido el tema
of pensions is until the minor
de las pensiones es hasta que el menor
achieves economic autonomy to fend
alcance autonomía económica para valerse
for themselves and reaches a level similar to that they
por sí mismo y alcance un nivel parecido
have with their parents or similar and
al que tiene con sus padres o similar y
the 18 years was when you started
lo de los 18 años era cuando se empezaba
working at 14 or 15 or 17
a trabajar con 14 años o con 15 o con 17
with  At 18 you can already have a more
con 18 ya puedes tener una economía más
or less solvent economy but at 18 years old it doesn't
o menos solvente pero de 18 años no
make any sense. So it's until
tiene ningún sentido Entonces es hasta
the child has a similar economy,
que el niño tenga una economía parecida
therefore it's going to be very difficult for
por lo tanto va a ser muy difícil que
that pension to ever be withdrawn from Ana María
esa pensión se retire nunca de Ana María
and the minor. By the way, luckily
al y del menor Por cierto con suerte que
here we are happy to do it,
acá nos está encantado de hacerlo con
luckily the Canon of saying it was an idea and
suerte la Canon de decir fue una idea y
a proposal from José Ortega Cano, it
una proposición de José Ortega Cano no
was not a request, therefore
fue ninguna petición por lo tanto la
María has nothing to do, what's
María no tiene nada que hacer lo que
missing is to ratify that possibly if it was
falta es ratificar que posiblemente si
not ratified on Friday it can be
no se ratificó el viernes se puede
ratified on Tuesday because that's like
ratificar el martes porque eso es como
if you have to go it's not the same but to make it
si tienes que ir no es igual pero para
understandable it's like you have to go
que se entienda es como se tiene que ir
play and sign signatures in two minutes and
a jugar a firmar firmas en dos minutos y
you just leave, so that's the
te vas nada más entonces eso es el
divorce. Now with the other issue that we have
divorcio ahora que con el otro tema que
also published this week in
hemos publicado también esta semana en
the newspaper, the issue is
el diario el tema es
why the divorce Ana María, the don
porque el divorcio Ana María el don ya
José Ortega has not taken it expensively.
José Ortega caro no se lo ha llevado
Enrique Trebolle Enrique Trebolle is
Enrique trebolle Enrique trebolle es el
José Ortega Cano's lawyer in
abogado de José Ortega Cano en los
recent years, even when the
últimos años incluso cuando el tema
criminal issue of the accident in which
penal de del accidente en el que
Parra died and the lawyer who was
falleció Parra y el abogado que estaba
in fact was the lawyer because  He is going
de hecho era el abogado porque él se va
to a prison in Zaragoza because
a una prisión de Zaragoza porque el
Enrique Trebolé's office is in
despacho de Enrique trebolé está en
Zaragoza. In other words, in fact, there is so much
Zaragoza Es decir de hecho viene tanta
relationship because of that and the decision is made to put him in prison
relación por eso y se decide la prisión
outside of Zaragoza because the lawyer
de fuera en Zaragoza porque el abogado
is in Zaragoza. That is to say, the issue is one and the other
está en Zaragoza ese tema es uno y otro
is the issue of what is going to happen now.
es el tema de qué va a pasar ahora pues
Josuértelano has been watching for two months now
josuértelano lleva ya dos meses viendo
how Ana María Aldo, now that they are
como Ana María Aldo una vez que ya están
divorced, continues on the program
divorciados continúa en el programa
where she collaborates, talking about
donde colabora hablando de la intimidad
José Ortegano's intimacy. Beyond the
de José ortegano Más allá de las
humiliations that she has been doing these
humillaciones que esté haciendo estos
last few days, about whether I have a ring,
últimos días de si tengo un anillo
because then I am going to tell myself that
porque entonces me voy a decir que eso
in the end these are moral baseness. That is to say, from
al final son bajezas Morales Es decir de
people with very little, with very little
personas con muy poca con muy poca
empathy, apart from education and little morals.
empatía aparte de Educación y poca moral
But that is one thing and another thing is what has been
Pero eso es una cosa y otra cosa eso lo
told in the last three
que se ha contado en los últimos tres
months about Ana María. Well, if
meses de Ana María Pues si
one thing happened, if others happened and
pasaba una cosa si pasaba otras y
then they slept, yes, they didn't sleep. If my
entonces dormían si no dormían si mi
family is Josuértelano's, they have
familia es la de josuértelano se han
behaved very badly with me because they did not pay attention to me,
portado muy mal conmigo porque no me
because they humiliated me. That
hacían caso porque me humillaban Eso sí
is actionable. That is to say, when I say if it is
es demandable Es decir cuando digo si es
actionable, say article 18
demandable decir el artículo 18
substitution  uses three concepts honor
sustitución utiliza tres conceptos honor
intimacy family and personal and self-
intimidad familiar y personal y propia
image that is not one they are three
imagen eso no es uno son tres conceptos
totally different concepts honor is one
totalmente distintos el honor es uno la
intimacy family and personal is another and
intimidad familiar y personal es otro y
self-image is another me what
la propia imagen es otro yo lo que
we published in the in the newspaper and we
nosotros publicamos en el en el diario y
published it this week I think it was
lo publicamos esta semana creo que fue
Wednesday is because in a
el miércoles es porque en una
conversation that I was having with
conversación en la que mantengo con
Enrique
Enrique
talking between colleagues well of course
hablando entre compañeros pues claro
he tells me that the only
pues él me dice que la única demanda
possible demand that each time for
posible que cada vez por intimidad
personal and family intimacy why Because we
personal y familiar por qué Porque se
talk about the family and above all there is one
habla de la familia y sobre todo hay una
thing that gains the same whether it is true or
cosa que gana lo mismo que sea verdad
false to say what Ana
mentira decir lo que ha contado Ana
María el don has said is a lie that the family
María el don es mentira que la familia
that Carmen that she was in the basement
que Carmen que ella estaba en el sótano
sewing because the basement because
cosiendo porque el sótano porque
then she was that is a soap opera that has already
entonces se encontraba eso es una novela
increased to continue
que se ha incrementada ya para continuar
Because the only way to be able to
Porque la única manera de poder
continue on television I remember
continuar en televisión yo recuerdo hace
many years ago in the theater I was in the
muchos años en el teatro estaba en el
theater also amaia there is an
teatro también amaia que hay una
exhibition of some friends of Ortega
exposición de de unos amigos de Ortega
Cano and tonight marilichol was going and
Cano y esta noche iba marilichol y
then I was playing
entonces yo estaba haciendo
the friend who came out who is a bit
la amiga que salió que está un poco con
truthful when she starts talking
toda la verdad cuando empieza a hablar
about Ana María el don What happens is that
de Ana María el don Lo que pasa que
well she is also older now and  She doesn't
bueno también está ya mayor y tampoco
want to get into that either, everyone there knows
quiere meterse en eso todos saben allí
Who is Ana Maria, the don? Yes, that's the
Quién es Ana María el don Sí esa es la
reality, okay, all right, let's see They've always
realidad vale todo bueno a ver Siempre
had a bad image of her, let's keep
han tenido una mala imagen de ella las
things as they are, they've never trusted her much,
cosas como son nunca han confiado mucho
but no, not that much. That night I
pero no no tanto yo aquella noche
remember that she was under the sun,
recuerdo que está bajo sol acá no estaba
marilichol wasn't here and I asked her about Ana
marilichol y yo le pregunté por Ana
Maria, then they tell me that she was, that she
María entonces me dicen que estaba que
was in the
estaba en el
workshop, the workshop was the basement,
en el taller el taller era el sótano que
when we talk about the basement it seems like it's
cuando hablamos del sótano parece que es
the basement of my grandmother's house, an
el sótano de la casa de mi abuela casa
abandoned house, we're not talking about a
abandonada no estamos hablando de una
lower part that is conditioned
parte de abajo que está condicionada
even with a kitchen and that's where she set up
hasta con cocina y es donde ella montó
the workshop to study and to do her
el taller para estudiar y para hacer sus
things because she was in her husband's house,
cosas porque estaba en la casa de su
so at no time did she say she did.
marido entonces en ningún momento decir
So she didn't go
ella Entonces no iba
to the events that her husband and
a los eventos que tenía su marido y los
her husband's friends had because she didn't
amigos de su marido porque no le
feel like it, that's her right, but don't
apetecía que está en su derecho pero no
say now that they pushed you out, they kicked you out
digas ahora que tú te apartaban te
Because look, I've never told it
echaban Porque mira no lo he contado
but I'm going to tell it today Tell me, I
nunca pero lo voy a contar hoy Cuéntame
think it was June 18, 2018, I
creo que fue el 18 de junio del año 2018
'm trying to remember, eh? Later, if you
estoy haciendo memoria eh después si tú
can look at it there to see if the
puedes mirarlo ahí a ver si coincide la
date matches, because no, no  I have never told it
fecha porque no no lo he contado nunca
on June 18,
el 18 de junio
2018, it takes place in Florida par
del año 2018 tiene lugar en Florida par
in Madrid in the Florida Park room,
en Madrid en la sala Florida Park la
Ana María Aldon's graduation, yes when she
graduación de Ana María aldon sí cuando
finished the design and pattern making, which I think she
terminó lo de diseño y patronaje que
is doing very little after, I
creo que después está haciendo muy poco
mean, she is doing the design of her
es decir está haciendo el diseño de su
new life, her new life that she has the
nueva vida de su nueva vida que tiene su
right to, but when María says it is that
derecho pero cuando dice la María es que
the family pushed me aside because the
la familia a mí me apartaba porque la
family did not like me, that night I
familia a mí no me quería yo esa noche
saw two people cry,
vi llorar a dos personas
Carmen Ortega Cano and Conchos de
a Carmen Ortega Cano ya Conchos de
Arcano, from the snub she did to her, yes, they
arcano del desplante que le hizo sí
were emotional and Carmen was very
estaban emocionadas y Carmen estaba muy
congested from the snub that
congestionada desde el desplante que le
Ana María Aldon did to her two sisters-in-law
hizo Ana María aldon a sus dos cuñadas
there. By the way, on the day of the graduation,
allí Por cierto el día de la graduación
Ana María del Don's family was not there,
la familia de Ana María del Don no
only her daughter because she was a model, or a
Solamente su hija porque era modela o
model, I say model in case any of
modelo que digo modelo por si alguna de
these who feel offended, a model, which
estas que se siente ofendida modela que
is even better, to be
todavía es mejor
able to,
poder
so her family was not there,
entonces allí no estaba su familia allí
her two sisters-in-law were there, Carmen Conchi, and
estaban sus dos cuñadas Carmen conchi y
I don't remember if
estaba también yo no recuerdo si estaba
Paco Ortega Cano was there and Carmen
Paco Ortega Cano y el marido de Carmen
Aniceto's husband when she says the humiliation that
Aniceto cuando dice ella la humillación
those two women suffered at the hands
que sufrieron esas dos mujeres de parte
of Ana María del Don, you know, we know that
de Ana María del Don sabe lo sabemos
those of us who were close and saw how
quienes estuvimos cerca y vimos como
Carmen had to stay back from the
Carmen se tuvo que estar para atrás del
snub that Ana María del Don gave her,
desplante que le hizo Ana María aldon
that is the reality, leaving her as if she
esa es la realidad pues dejarla como si
were a stranger,
fuera una desconocida en la
ignoring her. Yes, there were all of them in the way
ningunearla Sí ahí sobraban todos ellos
and that was Ana María towards her sisters-in-law, the ones who
y eso fue Ana María hacia su cuñadas las
are so bad, the ones who have behaved
que son tan malas las que se han portado
so badly that they were not welcomed, the ones they
tan malas que no eran acogido la que la
call the border, etc., etc. that is what
llaman frontera etcétera etcétera eso es
she has done, that is to say, and then something else,
lo que ha hecho ella es decir y después
the only one who has humiliated Ana
otra cosa la única que ha humillado Ana
María del Don, you know that it has not been her
María el don sabes que no ha sido su
daughter,
hija
her daughter, the only one who has not looked after her, it has
su hija la única que no ha mirado ha
been her daughter, it has not been anyone else, that is to
sido su hija no ha sido nadie más es
say, we have also published that
decir que eso también lo hemos publicado
in the, in the in the newspaper, I think that
en el en el en el diario creo que hace
a month ago the first time that
un mes la primera vez que llegó la hija
Ana María el don's daughter arrived at Ana
de Ana María el don a la casa de Ana
María el don's house when she was already living in the Aldea de
María el don cuando ya vivía en aldea de
Fresno in Madrid with her, with Ortega
Fresno en Madrid con su con la Ortega
Cano, the phrase that her daughter said to her
Cano la frase que le dijo su hija a su
mother is, you already have what you wanted, a
madre es ya tienen lo que querías una
big house and a rich guy,
casa grande y a un tipo rico
it's true, it's true, you
es verdad es verdad
already have what  that I wanted they
Ya tienes lo que quería
already have what you wanted a big house
ya tienen lo que querías una casa grande
very offended but man let's see the
muy ofendida pero hombre a ver la
family The family took it the wrong way not
familia La familia se lo tomó a mal no
the fact that she got
el hecho de que ella se quedara
pregnant As soon as it's to say one thing
embarazada Tan pronto es decir una cosa
is that but the family surprised as it would
es que pero la familia sorprendió como
surprise us all I think in
nos sorprendería yo creo que a todos en
that circumstance that doesn't take away from the fact that
esa circunstancia eso no quita a que
José Ortega didn't get into that bed
José Ortega no se metió en esa cama
because he wanted to no one pushed him Of course
porque quiso que nadie lo empujó Claro
no one pushed him and the issue is when it is told
que nadie lo empujó y el tema es cuando
when these
se cuenta cuando se cuentan estas
stories are told turning it around Not you, not
historias dándole la vuelta No a ti no
your million never no one you Carmen
tu millón nunca nadie a ti Carmen te
accepted you perfectly they didn't ask you
acepto perfectamente a ti no te pidieron
But I can't talk about that issue
Pero de ese tema sí que no puedo hablar
because it is a matter that is in
porque es un tema que está en la
court and there is still no sentence
justicia y todavía no hay sentencia
when it has been said that the niece said that she had
cuando se ha contado que la sobrina dijo
said that the child was not
que había dicho que el hijo no era de
José's that is a lie but if that is what she
José eso una patraña pero si eso lo
told Yes that is the first thing that was said
contó Si eso es lo primero que lo contó
was Ana María the don
fue Ana María el don
that we no longer remember the first one who
que no tenemos ya memoria la primera que
said it insinuated it was her it was nobody
lo dijo lo insinuó fue ella no fue nadie
and there yes within the family of José
y ahí sí dentro de la familia de José
Ortega Cano there are sisters who are more
Ortega Cano hay hermanas que son más
well known But there are nieces that he
conocidas Pero hay sobrinas que se las
has put them in and  that are not known and that's as far as I
ha metido y que no son conocidas y hasta
can go because it is a
ahí puedo leer porque eso sí es un
criminal process that the office is carrying out and I
proceso penal que lleva el despacho y
can't say more until there is a
que no puedo contar más hasta que haya
sentence and there is a lot left in that process.
sentencia y le queda mucho a ese proceso
What phase is
En qué fase está
this in? Well, it is for the first
este Bueno pues está para primera
instance
instancia
so that outside of honor because this
para que fuera del honor porque esto
would be what
sería la
you say what you say is the
que tú dices lo que tú dices es la
lawsuit, that is to say, what is being raised by the
demanda es decir que se plantea el
office of Mr. Enrique Trebolle of his
despacho de don Enrique trebolle de su
client José Ana María Aldon, that is to say, what would be
cliente José Ana María aldon es decir lo
possible would be for personal and family privacy
posible sería por intimidad personal y
why but no, I would not do it and because I
por qué pero no yo no lo haría y porque
think that they are not going to do it that I
creo que yo no lo van a hacer que yo no
am not in that office because in the end the
estoy en ese despacho porque al final el
honor, that is to say José Ortega here does not have
honor es decir José Ortega acá no tiene
a positive and negative honor. José here did not
un honor positivo y negativo José acá no
appear a month ago on Ana
salía hace un mes en el programa de Ana
Rosa Quintana's program saying not even semen has
Rosa Quintana diciendo ni semen tiene
strength
fuerza
that that is not an animal but the thing is that
que eso no es ningún animal pero es que
then what you cannot defend is
entonces lo que no puedes defender es el
my honor it is one thing when you appear
honor mío es una cosa cuando tú apareces
on a plate and many times in
en un plato y en muchas veces en
phone calls in interventions
llamadas telefónicas en intervenciones
in the street, honor there in the end he
en la calle el honor ahí al final él
himself has drawn an honor
mismo se ha dibujado un honor
regardless of whether he was a
independientemente de que haya sido
bullfighter and his own image is
matador de toros y la propia imagen está
closely related to honor. With what
muy relacionada con el honor Con qué se
can you sue or what way through
puede demandar o por qué vía por la
family and personal privacy because it is
intimidad familiar y personal porque es
the only way to be able to
la única la única manera de poder
obtain something and that is how I see it and I think there
obtener algo y es como yo lo veo y creo
is a coincidence and of course
que hay coincidencia y por supuesto
distancing myself from it because Enrique I
alejándome a distancia porque Enrique te
will be 40 years older than you in the profession and I
voy a llevar 40 años en el oficio y yo
am an apprentice in this just like in the
soy un Aprendiz de esto igual que en el
world of journalism, I am 22 and I already
mundo del periodismo yo 22 y ya el
see the headline right away in the world of
titular lo veo enseguida en el mundo del
law it is
derecho
very little time and the only thing I do
muy poco tiempo y lo único que hago
every day is try to learn something
todos los días es intentar aprender algo
something new but I would go for
algo nuevo pero que yo iría por
privacy anyway for me the
intimidad de todas maneras a mí la parte
privacy part no And the image itself
de la intimidad no Y la propia imagen
as I came or I come from the world of
como venía o Vengo del mundo de la
information is much much
información me resulta mucho más mucho
easier for me then that lawsuit without being
más fácil entonces esa demanda sin ser
because they have asked me days but
porque me han preguntado días pero se va
the lawsuit is going to be filed I do not know what is going to be
a interponer la demanda No sé lo que va
done because I am not in that
a hacer porque yo no estoy en ese
office If I were I could not
despacho Si estuviera no lo podría
tell it, I mean that they are seeing it
contar es decir que están viéndolo
because when a client comes to an
porque cuando un cliente llega un
office first you have to see if it is
despacho primero hay que ver si es
possible to say above all It is not that it is
posible decir sobre todo No es que sea
possible to sue if there is a possibility of
posible demandar si hay posibilidad de
winning, of winning, you always win in court
ganar de ganar se gana en sala siempre
when they say this when some
cuando dicen esto cuando dicen algunos
offices say This is winning no  you win
despachos Esto está ganando no se gana
in the room, nothing is ever won, you win
en sala nunca está ganado nada se gana
when you are already in it, in the room, then you have to
cuando se está ya en el en sala entonces
tell him There are possibilities of
hay que decirle Hay posibilidades de
winning, but if you don't see any,
ganar pero si no se ve ninguna pues
then back off, that it is a
entonces Echa para atrás que sea una
threat. Look, I think it is a threat, not
amenaza Mira yo creo es una amenaza no
from José Ortega Cano, to say he is tired, he is
de José Ortega Cano decir está cansado
tired of every
está cansado de que todos los fines de
weekend. Ana María, the one who did design and
semana Ana María la que hizo diseño y
pattern making, was going to be a star, not
patronaje iba a ser una estrella no
decibels from Paris and such, and Milan. I am
decibeles de París y tal y Milán estoy
using the same thing, you are, I want to
utilizando lo mismo tú estás quiero
separate, perfect, since the year 81 there is
separar perfecto desde el año 81 existe
a divorce law, what you cannot do is
la ley del divorcio lo que no puedes es
now, this afternoon, I mean, that is no longer,
ahora esta tarde es decir es que eso ya
that is not suable, it is baseness. Well, I
no eso no es demandable es bajeza Pues
have a ring trying to play, if I would make her
tengo un anillo intentando jugar si le
then the girls, I It was from
haría entonces las niñas yo Ha sido de
the other one, the one who came from Mexico, I don't know
la otra la que vino de México no sé de
where she came from, she is from Los Morros swollen
dónde vino está de Los Morros hinchados
to tell if Well, that is already that it is
para contar si Bueno pues eso ya es que
not known because she needs today it has already
no se sabe porque necesita hoy ya ha
cost less, she can tell less
costado menos ya puede contar menos
because the truth is that in the end you only
porque la verdad que al final solamente
learn when they splash you
se escarmienta cuando te salpican
financially,
económicamente
it is that when they splash you financially
es que cuando te salpican económicamente
when they tell you it is 40,000 euros,
cuando te dicen son 40.000 euros
the only way you
la única manera
want a civil liability
que quieres una responsabilidad civil
is to go to prison  I don't know that prison
que vaya a prisión no sé que la prisión
costs all of us Spaniards money, that's to
nos cuesta dinero a todos los españoles
say it's better for the civil one that they pay you, we
ya es decir mejor por la civil que te
leave prisons for other
paguen dejamos las cárceles para otras
things because prison costs
cosas que la cárcel nos cuesta mucho
all of us Spaniards a lot of money and for that they
dinero a todos los españoles y para ello
go, for example, Griñán, okay, for
que vayan por ejemplo griñán vale por
example, the the
ejemplo la la
several questions, okay, several questions, it's
varias preguntas vale varias preguntas
possible because, of course,
cabe la posibilidad porque claro a ver
José has no way of
José no tiene ninguna manera de
prohibiting you from talking about me because
prohibirle no puedes hablar de mí porque
in the end it's part of his life and Ana María
al final es parte de su vida y Ana María
Ardón is well known because she has been with
ardón es conocida porque ha estado con
El Torero, so José has no
El Torero entonces José no tiene ninguna
possibility of prohibiting her from talking about
posibilidad de prohibirle que hable de
him. Unless, for example, I can think of
él A no ser que haya por ejemplo que se
a clause within the
me ocurra a mí una cláusula dentro del
divorce agreement, no, it's likely that
acuerdo del divorcio no si es probable
this clause that cannot be talked about
esta cláusura de que no se puede hablar
anymore about our married life is prohibited. Let's
más de nuestra vida matrimonial vamos a
see, I think that I, the the
ver yo creo que yo la la el acuerdo de
divorce agreement, I don't have to say, I don't
divorcio yo no lo tengo decir yo no
know if there is any clause that has
conozco si hay alguna cláusula que se
been filed, I imagine not since it is
haya Interpuesto me imagino que no al
by mutual agreement and that Ana María
ser de mutuo acuerdo y que Ana María
cannot immediately prohibit it, among other
enseguida no se puede prohibir entre las
things, because in the end, María
cosas porque al final a María habla
also talks about her experiences, she talks about what she has
también de sus vivencias habla de lo que
lived through, but one thing  talk about what
ha vivido pero una cosa hablar de lo que
one has lived and another thing is to talk about
uno ha vivido y otra cosa es hablar de
what I have lived, splashing my
lo que yo he vivido salpicando a mi
husband, my husband's family and in
marido de la familia de mi marido y de
fact the article is personal
hecho el artículo es intimidad personal
and family intimacy and José Ortega
y familiar y la familia de José Ortega
Cano's family is also his brothers, his
Cano también es sus hermanos sus
sisters and so on, so of course you
hermanas y demás entonces Claro que
can talk but one thing is to talk and
puede hablar pero una cosa es hablar y
another thing is to tell intimacies
otra cosa es ya contar intimidades
even if they are yours but if there is an
aunque sean tuyas pero si hay una
intimacy they can be from both of the
intimidad pueden ser de los dos de la
other side that
otra parte
is where you can legally attack
ya es donde sí se puede atacar
and of the statements that
y de las de las declaraciones que ha
Ana María has made,
hecho Ana María
which one do you think could be condemnable
Cuál crees tú que podría ser condenable
of all the ones she has said,
de todas las que ha dicho
let's see Javi. I have not seen them, I have not
vamos a ver Javi No las he visto no las
seen them all because it is impossible
he visto todas porque es imposible
because she spends five hours on Saturdays and
porque se tira cinco horas los sábados y
Sundays and on Sundays,
los domingos y yo los domingos los
Saturdays I have theater. On Sundays I
sábados tengo teatro Los domingos me
would like to do other things and then
gustaría hacer otras cosas y después
during the week I take everything I
entre semana voy cogiendo todo lo que
can to stay informed because I
puedo para estar informado porque yo
have to write. I think that there are two
tengo que escribir Yo creo que hay dos
hotels that can be sharpened because
hoteles que se pueden sacar punta porque
Ana María has said little but I have
Ana María ha dicho poco pero he
insinuated a lot and the insinuation
insinuado mucho y la insinuación también
is also not a crime because the
es no delito porque se penal la
insinuation of insidious information is punishable  you
insinuación de información insidiosa
can also sue and Maria Between
también se puede demandar y María Entre
the silence that face of not broken in a
el silencio esa cara de no roto en un
with banana and I don't want to get wet her
con plátano y no me quiero mojar su
silences and her insinuations have been
silencios y sus insinuaciones han sido
very powerful I don't remember exactly the
muy potentes no recuerdo exactamente las
statements Well I think that one night one
declaraciones Pues creo que una noche un
day she said something the bed existed if
día contó algo existía la cama si ya no
you didn't work anymore if it worked if it was
usted funcionaba si funcionaba si era
better if it was worse as a result
mejor si era peor a raíz de
of the blunder because it was a
de la metedura de pata porque fue una
blunder of bear from here not from
metedura de pata de osor de acá no de
reading a text that
leer un texto que ni siquiera había
he hadn't even written in a program that reads it badly
escrito él en un programa que lo lee mal
read that he doesn't write because he doesn't
leído que él no escribe porque no
write So it will have been written to you I
escriba Así que se lo habrá escrito me
imagine that someone close who
imagino que alguien de cercano que
knows a little about the law making a fool of himself
conoce un poco el derecho hacer ridículo
in that way because it places you At the same
de esa manera pues te sitúa Al mismo
level as the other I extend the other
nivel que la otra extiendo la otra más
younger one and being faster because you are
joven y siendo más rápida porque tú ya
no longer fast nor are you young nor are you
no está ni rápido ni eres joven ni eres
brilliant So from that blunder well there were
brillante Entonces de esa metedura pues
already many intimacies told well if he
ahí ya se contaron muchas intimidades
was lazy if it didn't
pues ya pues si era flojo si no
work if the day he left at his
funcionaba si el día que se iba en su
house and there were many and many and all that is what
casa y había muchas y muchos y todo eso
family intimacy is
es lo que es la intimidad familiar
one thing that when they say is that they
una cosa que cuando dicen es que se
sue they sue  María can be
demanda se demandan a María se puede
sued, Ana María, but after doing a
demandar Ana María pero después hacer un
live show there is a
directo hay una responsabilidad
subsidiary and joint liability, which always falls
solidaria subsidiaria que eso siempre es
on the network. Well, sorry, the
a la cadena bueno Perdón al programa ese
program is a production company or the network, it
programa es una productora o a la cadena
's not the one that can't pay, there is a
no es aquella no pueda pagar hay una
liability that can be joint
responsabilidad que puede ser solidaria
or it can be joint and several, that if
o puede ser subsidiaria solidaria que si
I don't pay, the person above pays, and the
yo no pago paga el de arriba y
liability between two people.
subsidiaria entre dos
Well, I think it's clear
Pues yo creo que ha quedado claro
[Music]
[Música]